每次拿报纸都给库斯曼 做免费心理治疗.
I gotta figure out a way to get the morning paper...
下次得想想办法
without having to give Ellen Koosman a free diagnosis.
我的报道刊登了吗？
Well, is my story in?
-好像搞错了 -什么？
- Oh, they've made a terrible mistake. - What? What?
他们把你的报道放在头条了!
Well, they put your story on the front page!
说真的？
Are you serious?
"Major Long Island developer offers bribe to County officials...
作者：麦姬.海狸
"by Margaret Beaver."
不!
Oh, no!
是麦姬.西弗
No, it's Margaret Seaver.
这还多亏了你
Oh, honey, I owe you for this.
要不是你留在家，让我出去工作.
If you hadn't moved your practice home so I could try my career again...
我哪来的上头版？
I'd never be on Page 1.
若是真的心存感激.
Well, if you really think you owe me one...
你大可以署名“杰森.西弗的老婆”
next time they give you a by-line why don't you have it read, Mrs. Jason Seaver?
快点把话说完
Don't hold your breath.
感激已经没有了
So much for gratitude.
我要换装上班
Well, I'd better change before work.
这不是工作服？
These aren't your work clothes?
今早更衣时，我还是第六版的作者
Well, when I put this on this morning, I was a Page 6 writer...
现在要换成头版的装扮
and now I have to dress for Page 1.
我需要一份工作
I need a good job.
-孩子啊，还是读书好啊 -不，不
- No, don't be a fool. Stay in school. - No, no.
今天我们要调查人们工作的一天.
Today's the day we're supposed to observe someone at work...
准备明天劳动节发言
so we can do a talk about it tomorrow at Career Day.
那？
So?
我原本打算调查凯西的爸爸
I was all set to do mine on Cathy Dunne's dad.
他是个股票经纪人
He's a stockbroker.
可是凯西刚刚来电 她爸虽然工龄32年.
And Cathy just called to tell me that they fired her father...
却一下子被解雇了
after 32 years with the company.
我今早真是倒霉
Talk about wrecking my morning.
其他人的工作也满有意思的
Well, you know, you do know some other people with interesting jobs.
说一个看看
Name one.
你身边有个人，他专注于他的职业
Somebody very close to you happens to be a dedicated professional...
他讲究穿着，他是一家之主
who also heads up a family and is a pretty snappy dresser.
对了!妈妈!
Of course! Mom!
我是说我
I was talking about me, Carol.
爸爸，我需要真正的那种工作
But, Dad, I need someone with a real job.
妈？
Mother?
坏八怪!
Phlegm-face!
爸爸，我不舒服
Dad, I think I'm sick.
凯罗 有些人认为心理医生是真正的职业
Carol, you know, some people think psychiatry is a real job.
不信就算了
Fine, fine, don't believe me.
爸，我病了，量量我的体温
Dad, I'm sick. Here, take my temperature.
好的，测体温还是肛温？
Okay. Oral or the old-fashioned way?
(English Subtitle) Growing.Pains.S01E2 -= The.Career.Decision =- Subripped by zerox
太棒了，不用上学!
All right, no school!
我要一份煎蛋，要全熟的 两片猪肉.
I'll have a fried egg, over easy, two strips of bacon...
一片肉桂面包再加一点果冻
a slice of cinnamon toast with just a touch of jelly.
-炉子里有麦粥 -太好了
- There's oatmeal on the stove. - Perfect.
妈妈也说是好主意
Mom says it's a great idea.
麦克，我今天不用上学
Mike, I'm not going to school today.
我一整天只需要帮妈妈录音
I'm spending the whole day recording Mom.
我一整天只需要无所事事
I'm spending the whole day at home doing nothing.
大家好
Hi, guys.
亲爱的，我得上路了 免得流言蜚语.
Oh, honey, I gotta run. I don't want people saying:
“麦姬这下红了 上班就可以姗姗来迟”
"Now that Maggie's a star reporter, she's coming in late."
于是迅速吻了她的家人.
Thus with a quick kiss to the people she calls her family...
记者忙碌的一天要揭开帷幕了
a hectic day in the typical pell-mell world of a great reporter begins.
杰森，请帮忙洗衣服
Oh, and Jason, could you do that extra load of laundry, if you get a chance?
家庭琐事抛诸脑后，她出发了
With petty thoughts of home behind her, she heads off...
迈入了这个残酷的.
into the cruel unknown that is...
未知的世界
the real world.
-你在干什么？ -康复中
- What are you doing? - Healing.
若是有精力打游戏机.
Mike, if you're well enough for video games...
我15分钟内送你到学校吧
I can have you at school in 15 minutes.
爸爸，我给你添麻烦了
Oh, I hope I'm not too much trouble, Dad.
若是头脑清醒了，课本就放在你跟前
If your head clears, remember those school books are right in front of you.
我感到耳边嗡嗡作响
Now I'm hearing bells.
库斯曼，我现在很忙..进来吧
Ellen Koosman. I'm so busy right now, I've been... Please, come in.
马上就好了
I can only stay a second.
我是过来借酵母粉的
I wanted to know if I could borrow some dry yeast from you.
本来今早打算去市场，只是脚太累了
I was gonna go to the store this morning, but my legs were so tired.
也许是吃了医生的药所致.
I don't know if it's the pills that the doctor gave me...
也许是天气不好所致
or if it's the weather that's causing...
-嗨，麦克 -嗨，我病了
- Hi, Mike. - Hey, I'm sick.
-我去拿酵母粉 -谢谢
- I'll get some yeast. - Thank you.
我要烘些面包送汤
I wanted to bake some bread to go with the soup that I'm making.
我感冒了，真是难以置信.
Now I'm coming down with a cold. Can you believe it?
这个冬天真是祸不单行
All winter long it's been one thing after the other.
大脚趾头也发炎了
And now I've got a bunion on my big toe.
西弗医生，你得救救我
Dr. Seaver, you've got to help me.
我原来是个男儿身的姑娘
I feel like a woman trapped in a man's body.
也是个坏陋的姑娘
Not a very pretty one, either.
-哈尔，你好 -杰森，你好
- How you doing, Hal? - How are you, Jason?
见到你太好了，进来吧
Good to see you. Come on in.
还记得麦姬吗？
You remember Maggie.
我还以为自己记得呢
I thought I did.
其实这是隔壁的库斯曼 这是哈尔医生
Actually, this is Ellen Koosman, our next door neighbor. Dr. Miller.
你也是个医生？
Oh, so you're a doctor, too.
我这下面疼得厉害.
I have this terrible pain right here below...
哈尔医生是兽医
Dr. Miller is a veterinarian.
我家的德国狗掉毛了
There's a bald spot on my schnauzer.
满逗人的，就在这个位置.
It's really funny. Right here. It's got this thing that's...
你赶时间是吧？
I know you can't stay.
-幸会 -幸会
- Nice to meet you, Doctor. - Nice meeting you.
幸好你没告诉她我是心理医生
Thanks for not telling her I'm a psychiatrist.
我现在没有病人
I'm in between patients now.
-进办公室聊吗？ -好的
- You want to come in the office? - Yeah, sure.
-这就是你的办公室？ -哈尔，在家工作很舒服
- This is your office? - Hal, working at home is great, really.
我明白你为什么厉害纽约的公司了
I can see why you left your position at Long Island General.
来吧，废话少说
All right, let's get it over with.
你这次要来说服我.
You're gonna tell me all the reasons...
离职是愚蠢的.
you think I was foolish to quit.
不，我是来让你看看我的新作
No, I'd rather show you my latest book.
Wow.
"Sexual Dysfunctions of Middle Age."
也许对你有帮助
I figured you could use it.
幸好你对这个了解深入
Well, at least you're now writing something that you know about.
-让护士开门就行了 -她午休去了
- Why don't you let your nurse get that? - She's at lunch.
-现在是早上9点 -她是胖了点，但我喜欢
- It's 9:00 a.m. - She's a large woman, but I love her.
早上好!我是屋顶维修公司的杰里
Good morning, sir. How are you? I'm Jerry from Rapid Roofing.
-我家屋顶很好，谢谢 -车房天花漏水
- Well, our roof is fine, thank you. - Your garage leaks like a sieve.
谁说的？
Who said that?
隔壁光头狗的主人
The lady next door with the baldheaded dog.
-她不清楚.. -我马上就给你检查
- Well, she wouldn't know... - I'll check it out right now.
听我说.
No, it's... Listen. Hey.
爸，我现在有精神看电视了
Hey, Dad, I think I'm well enough to watch TV now.
不能看好看的节目
As long as you don't enjoy it.
大夫，在这里行医真是刺激
Oh, it's a real exciting little practice you got here, Doctor.
平时没那么冷清的
Well, it's not usually this quiet.
平时这房间里到处是疯子
Most of the time this house is crawling with people with mental problems.
想得美
Yeah, you wish.
好吧，客套话到此为之
All right, Jason, enough of this male bonding.
我要离开纽约的心理治疗院
I wanted to tell you that I'm leaving Long Island General.
-这么多年了.. -对，是时候.
- After all those years? - Yeah, I think it's time to move on.
做一些有意义的事情了
Do something really worthwhile for a change.
我要去洛杉矶做电台节目
I'm gonna do talk radio in LA.
洛杉矶
LA.
那里疯子多的是
You never run out of patients out there.
人事部要我推荐继任者.
Now, look, the board of directors wants me to pick my successor...
我推荐你
and I'm picking you.
-我？ -对，舍你其谁？
- Me? - Yeah, who better?
你曾对我说.
You know, you once told me you wanted to run this department...
40岁前要成为老总
by the time you were 40.
看来你可以提前3年了
Well, you're gonna be three years ahead of schedule.
-真的？ -我从来不拿工作或内衣来开玩笑
- Are you kidding? - I never kid about work or underwear.
这个.
This is...
这个太棒了，这机会.
This is incredible. This is the kind of opportunity I've...
-我不能接受 -什么？
- I can't take the job. - What?
我和麦姬现在有了协议
Now, you see... You see, Maggie... I have a deal with her now, Hal.
轮到她发展事业
She's taking a shot at her career.
杰森，这可是整个部门的总管
Jason, this is head of the entire department.
我办不到
I can't.
她现在正在腾飞，今早还上头版了
She's really rolling now, Hal. She was on the front page this morning.
-有看到吗？ -没看到
- Did you see it? - No, no.
杰森，机会难得啊
Look, Jason, how often do you get a chance like this?
37岁当部门主管
Department head at 37.
简直..匪夷所思
It's... It's impossible, Hal.
杰森，至少考虑一下吧
Jason, promise me you'll at least think about it.
我现在的人生.
Hal, my life right now is...
腐烂了!整个排水的东西没了
Dry rot! You're about to lose the whole weenie!
回到旋风的中心.
We're back in the eye of the storm...
烦嚣的小区日报编辑部
the frantic, fast-paced newsroom of the Long Island Daily Herald.
数十名记者呼啸而过
Dozens of reporters race around the room, feverishly.
-妈，你正在干什么？ -在找茶包
- Now what are you doing, Mom? - Looking for a tea bag.
找到了
Here it is.
下面要做些什么？
Then what are you gonna do?
首先泡一杯茶.
Well, first I'm going to make myself a cup of tea...
接着要找总编苏珊.
and then I'm gonna talk to Susan Rush...
谈谈我的报道的续集
my city editor, about the follow-up story I'm working on.
对了，你应该找苏珊聊聊
Hey, Carol, you should talk to Susan.
她能让你了解报业生涯
She could tell you all about a newspaper career.
她身为编辑，女性，年轻，咬字清晰.
She's an editor, a woman, young, articulate...
平时人很好
and she's a very sweet person.
麦姬
Maggie.
关于你的文章
About your article.
有位约瑟夫.查德威打电话来了.
I just got a call from a Joseph K. Chadway...
就是我负责的头版今早文章中的.
the builder you accused of bribing County officials...
你指责那个贿赂官员的建筑商
in the story I ran on Page 1 this morning.
约瑟夫.查德威对指控表示震惊.
Joseph K. Chadway was a little angry at being accused of bribery...
这当然了
I'll bet.
因为你把他的名字拼错了
...since the man you meant to accuse was Joseph A. Chadway.
我的妈呀
Holy moley.
我们的律师也是这种反应
Exactly what our lawyer said.
苏珊，我也不知道为什么.
Oh, Susan, I don't know how this possibly could have...
你竟然没有校对名字.
I just can't believe you didn't double-check the name.
这是基本常识呀
I mean, that's about as basic as it gets.
麦姬，续集不会交给你了.
Maggie, I am pulling you from the follow-up...
我得找一个真正的记者
and getting a real reporter.
她人确实很好，对不对？
Well, was I right? Is she nice or what?
播放中
It's on.
还在播
It's still on. Whoa!
她又要辞职了.
She'd have to quit again.
现在轮到我 另一个接受这份工的理由
And... Now I'm talking to myself. That's another reason to take the job.
-爸爸 -什么事？
- Hey, Dad. - What is it, Mike?
每天下午3：30 电视都会播放
Gilligan's Island is on every day at 3:30.
麦克，我很忙 我正面临一个痛苦的抉择
Mike, I'm very busy. I'm trying to make a tough decision here.
不管我看不看电视，它都在播放
Dad, Dad, it's on whether I watch it or not.
节目中的主角，那个富翁 他老婆，教授还有.
Gilligan, the Skipper, too. The millionaire, his wife, the Professor and...
-玛丽？ -对
- Mary Ann? - Exactly.
-你想说说什么？ -电视剧不是为了我而存在的
- What's the point? - Dad, it's not on for me.
总之就是播放中
It's just on.
麦克，开始意识到 世界不是以你为中心？
Mike, are you starting to realize that the world doesn't revolve around you?
是的
Yeah, I guess I am.
恭喜你
Well, congratulations.
你刚刚领悟到了加缪的哲学基本原理
You know, you've hit on one of the basic ideas in the philosophy of Camus.
加缪是那条杀人鲸？
The killer whale?
不，那是沙缪
No, Mike, that's Shamu.
失陪了，我要去弄干衣机
Excuse me, I have to empty the dryer.
-来，我可以展示给你看 -不了，谢谢
- Here, Dad, look, I can even show you. - That's okay, thanks.
校车!
The school bus.
-爸爸! -怎么了？
- Hey, Dad! - What? What is it?
你还不明白？
Don't you see?
若电视是这样，学校也一样
If Gilligan goes on without me, so does my school.
今天即使我不在 人们还是一样地过活
You know, all day today, life went on even though I wasn't there.
这是你第一次领悟哲学 我为你而自豪
Mike, this is your first philosophical realization. I'm proud of you.
看电视真的能学到东西
See, you can learn from TV.
今天世界没有了我还在转动
Dad, all day today life went on without me.
你也是.
And you, too.
-这个我不确定.. -爸爸
- Well, I'm not sure... - But, Dad.
你懂吗？这世界不需要我们
Don't you understand? The world doesn't need us anymore.
-没有我们也是好好的 -不要张冠李戴
- It does just fine without us. - Oh, speak for yourself, Mike.
这么一天就这么难受，你呢？
Gosh, if I feel like this after one day, how do you feel?
你是天天困在这里
I mean, you're stuck here every day.
困在这里？非也，我是选择在这里
Stuck! Michael, I'm not stuck. I'm here because I wanna be here.
不好意思，洗衣机叫我了
Now if you'll excuse me, my laundry's calling.
袜子兄弟，来了
Coming, socks.
就像漂流到“梦幻岛”上面的人
Trapped just like the castaways on Gilligan's isle.
为期3小时
A three-hour tour.
-爸爸! -凯罗，提早回家了？
- Dad, Dad! - Hi, Carol. You're home early.
-妈妈呢？ -在停车
- Where's Mom? - Parking her car.
听好，没时间解释了.
Listen, I don't have much time to explain...
今天是妈妈一辈子中最糟糕的一天
but Mom has had the worst day of her entire life.
为什么？
Why?
不要在刺激她了，可以吗？
Now, you can't do or say anything to upset her, okay?
什么事了？
But what happened?
-亲爱的 -提前下班了？
- Hi, honey. - Hi, home early, huh?
爸爸，不是说不要刺激她吗!
Dad, I told you not to upset her!
凯罗，我没事
Carol, I'm okay.
谢谢你的关心 不过我一直都说了，我没事
Now I appreciate your concern, but as I told you all afternoon, I'm fine.
什么事了？
What happened?
我和编辑有点矛盾
Oh, I had a disagreement with my editor.
她把妈妈骂得狗血临头.
Dad, she made Mom look like a complete...
凯罗
Carol.
录了音，你听听看
I've got it on tape, Dad. You decide.
凯罗，成年人说话你是不会懂的
No. Now, Carol, you just don't understand how adults talk to adults.
有时候成年人会骂人
Sometimes they yell.
没看过李敖的节目吗？
Haven't you seen the new Jack Klugman show?
原来是这样
Sure, sure, that must be it.
-什么事了？ -没什么
- What happened? - Oh, no big deal.
那好，听她的口气.
That's good. You know, the way she's carrying on...
-还以为是世界末日了 -不是
- I thought it was the end of the world. - No.
还记得心理治疗院里的哈尔吗？
Hey, you remember Hal Miller, doctor from Long Island General?
他今天过来了，还说.
Well, he came by here today, and he offered me...
-杰森.. -怎么了？
- Oh, Jason. - What?
今天是我最耻辱的一天
I have never been so humiliated in all my life.
亲爱的，怎么了？
Honey, what?
这不是说因为被骂.
It is not being yelled at that really bothered me, but...
甚至不是因为我的过错
Or even making the mistake to begin with.
-什么过错？ -我把K写成A了
- What mistake? - I used a "K" instead of an "A."
不是吧!
No!
-拼错了男人的名字 -那还好
- In a man's name. - Well, that's not so bad.
但文章是指控他的，他也许会告我们
Who will probably sue us because we said he was a felon.
那就麻烦了
That could be trouble.
-知道我最害怕什么吗？ -不知道
- But you know what really got to me? - No.
苏珊骂我的时候，我一直在想.
It's what kept going through my head when Susan was yelling at me.
想什么？
What?
我不应该工作，应该在家洗衣服
That instead of working I could be home doing the laundry.
而且听起来很合理
And it sounded good.
你看得不够透彻
Oh, you weren't thinking straight.
杰森，我碰到问题，需要你的意见
Oh, Jason, it's time I faced a few things and I need your advice.
-好 -好？
- Okay. - Okay?
在过去的一年中，我很害怕回去工作
Over this past year I've had a lot of fears about going back to work.
我能够继续18年前的职业吗？
Can I pick up right where I left off 18 years ago?
我能够兴比我小…四分之一的人竞争吗？
Can I compete with people half... Three-quarters my age?
我是喜欢我的工作 还是为了工作而工作？
Do I really want a career or is it the idea of having a career that I love?
这对孩子们公平吗？ 这对你公平吗？
Am I being fair to the kids? Am I being fair to you?
于是我模仿你
So I did what you always do.
-我列了两张表 -很好
- I started two lists. - Good.
一是继续工作的理由
One of reasons to keep my job.
空白的
See, it's blank.
另一张是辞职的理由
And the other of reasons to quit.
瞧瞧
Look at it.
-面包，牛奶，丝袜.. -不，反面
- "Bread, milk, pantyhose." - No, no, no, the other side.
还真多呢
Well, this is quite a list.
你认为呢？
So, what do you think?
让我决定你应否辞职？
Are you asking me if I think you should quit?
对
Yeah.
为什么偏偏在今天问我
Well, it's interesting that you should ask me this today of all days.
亲爱的，我需要你的意见 你能给我公正，客观的意见
Oh, honey, I need your advice. I know you'll be fair and objective.
是的
Yes.
在你不希望我回去时.
See, you were the one that advised me to go back to work...
是你建议我回去工作的
when in your heart of hearts you didn't want me to.
-是的 -这点我很欣赏
- Well, I did, yes. - Yes, and I love you for it.
谢谢
Thank you.
我相信这一次你也能公正，客观
So I know you'll be fair and objective here, too...
尽管你真的很想我辞职
even if you really wanted me to quit...
因为你在家真的不好受
because I know staying at home has to be getting to you.
-我.. -我因该辞职吗？
- Well, I've... - Should I quit?
-这真的难以定夺 -亲爱的，你认为怎样？
- That's tough, Maggie. - Honey, what do you think?
我认为如果你认为.
Well, I think that if you think...
回去工作是错误的.
that you've made a mistake going back to work...
那么你应该.
then I think... Then you should...
做些相应的补救
do something about it.
那.
Well.
不必说下去了
I guess that's all there is to say.
妈妈，我刚听到消息 虽然你是个破记者，我还是爱你
Mom, I just heard, and I still love you even if you are a rotten reporter.
-早上好 -省省吧，只有我在
- Good morning. - Save it. It's just me.
-位置是我的 -我帮你坐暖和而已
- Then get out of my chair. - I was just warming it for you.
位置是我的，走开
Out of my chair, squirt.
妈妈呢？
Where's Mom?
她提早去上班，要跟上司说清楚
She left for work early to clear some things up with her boss.
-你怎么知道？ -我个子小
- How do you know? - I'm small.
人们常常忽略我 什么事情都说出来了
People forget I'm around and say all kinds of things.
大家应该对妈妈说我们信任她
You guys should have told her that you still believe in her...
我们支持她
and that you're behind her.
有爸爸在，我们就不必了
Hey, Mom doesn't need to hear that from us as long as Dad's around.
这才是人们结婚的原因
That's what he's here for. That's why people get married.
结婚后，即使知道自己一文不值.
So that there's at least one person saying you're okay...
至少还会有一个人支持自己
when you know you're just a crummy bag of dog meat.
麦克，你说得对
Mike, you're absolutely right.
吃完收拾桌子，出去要锁门
You guys are gonna have to clean up here and lock the door when you leave.
我要追上妈妈，不然就迟了
I'm gonna go catch Mom before she makes a mistake.
小小的挫折，不该就此放弃
She shouldn't give up because of one little mistake.
这个妈妈知道
Hey, she knows that.
生了你以后，她不是继续生孩子吗？
I mean, after you were born she had another kid, didn't she?
可笑
That's funny.
拿着
Here.
昨天你说要请真正的记者来报道续篇
You said yesterday that you wanted a real reporter to do the follow-up to my story.
我就是真正的记者
Well, you've got one, me.
若是这里面还有错误 我就永远离开这里
You find anything wrong with that and I'm out of here for good.
若是里面没有错误，希望你能纳用
But if you don't find anything wrong with it, I expect you to use it...
写得不比这里的任何人差
because it's as good as anybody can do in this office.
说得对
You're right.
你这样做是不公正的..什么？
And I don't think it's very fair that you just... What?
我说“说得对”
I said, "You're right."
Oh.
她是胡说的，别当真
She doesn't know what she's saying. She doesn't mean a word of it.
-什么？ -我是说真的
- What? - Yes, I do.
-不是的 -是的
- No, you don't. - Yes, I do.
我只是不想让你辞职
I just want you to know that I don't want you to quit.
辞职？我没有要辞职
Quit! I am not going to quit.
-没有？ -没有
- No? - No.
不
No.
这里不是“每日行星报”？
This isn't the Daily Planet?
不好意思
Excuse me.
路易斯？
Lois?
克拉克？
Clark?
吉米？
Jimmy?
不好意思
Excuse me.
杰森，你在想些什么？
Jason, what were you thinking?
-那一点不好了？ -你想让我被解雇？
- At which embarrassing point? - Are you trying to get me fired?
不，我要阻止你辞职
No, I came down here to keep you from quitting.
昨天你才建议我辞职
Yesterday you told me to quit.
-那是个坏主意 -我都听你的
- Well, that was bad advice. - That I relied on.
今天赶过来就是要让你别听我的
Well, today I rushed down here to stop you from following it.
-你怎么没听我的？ -因为那是个坏主意
- Why didn't you follow it? - Because it was bad advice.
好吧，我承认
Okay, I admit it.
我当时希望你重新接管我们的家庭
I liked the idea of you coming back and taking over the house, Maggie.
我有束缚的感觉
I've been feeling trapped.
你认为心理治疗院是出路？
And you saw Long Island General as a way out?
你知道这事了？
You knew about that?
我今早出门时碰巧发现这个了
When I was leaving this morning I happened to find this.
“接受职位的理由，拒绝职位的理由”
"Reasons to take the job. Reasons to turn it down."
-你也看过了吧？ -是的
- Guess you probably read it, too. - Yup.
两边都看了
Both columns.
为什么不告诉我？
Jason, why didn't you tell me about the offer?
我怕你觉得我建议你辞职.
Well, because I didn't want it to seem like I was telling you to quit...
是因为我想把握机会
so that I could pursue my opportunity.
我确实是如此
Which I was.
你很想接受哈尔的工作吧？
You really want to take Hal's offer, don't you?
我考虑过
I considered it.
于是列了这张表
And then I made out this list and...
结果是否定的
it came out clearly against.
杰森，上面有9个理由接受工作 只有1个理由不接受
Jason, it's 9-to-1 in favor of taking the job.
是的，但不接受的理由是“因为麦姬”
Yes, but the one reason not to...
这比其他的理由都充分
the one called "Maggie," that's more important to me than all the rest.
你真好
You're terrific.
这才是公正的
Hey, well, it's only fair.
轮到我留在家里.
You know, I guess it's my turn to stay home...
陪陪里面的角色了
with Gilligan, and the Skipper, and the millionaire.
什么？
What?
这个你要问问麦克 他是家里的新哲学家
Well, you gotta ask Mike. He's the new philosopher of the family.
帕罗先生意识到自己普遍地 不受欢迎后.
Mr. Purlow's feelings of paranoia have been greatly reduced...
恐惧症大大减轻了
by the realization of the fact that he is indeed universally disliked.
-好的方面是.. -爸爸
- On the bright side... - Dad?
我在这里
In here, Carol.
劳动节怎样了？
Hi, honey. How was Career Day?
我发现大部分工作都是悬于一线的
Well, see, I realized that most jobs hang by a slender thread...
于是我决定不采访妈妈 而去采访苏丽凡的爸爸
so I decided not to do Mom's job and I did Emily Sullivan's father's job, instead.
-他做什么的？ -他是劳工部门文员
- What does he do? - He's a clerk at the unemployment office.
爸爸，好消息
Hey, great news, Dad.
我听到过不下百次了
If I heard it once, I heard it a hundred times today.
我病了，所有老师都说课堂大不相同
When I was sick, every teacher mentioned that it was not the same there...
因为没有我的胡言乱语打扰
without me disrupting class and making stupid comments.
-这算好消息？ -对我来说是
- That's great news? - Yeah, well, it is to me.
也许高一不是因为我而存在
I mean, the 10th grade may not revolve around me...
但我不在时，他们绝对知道
but they sure know when I'm not there.
凯罗，要开始播放了 这是我们控制以外的事
Hey, Carol, come on. Gilligan's on and we can't stop it.
心理学家的一天又结束了
Thus ends another day in the life of a great psychiatrist...
没有置身于大都会的医院中
not behind the facade of a big city hospital, but...
而是在此处真实的世界
right here in the real world.
[zeroxia@gmail.com] 2006.04.01